

\times

neerajchaurasia2013@gmail.

9718869466



Dadri, Gautam Buddha Nagar, India



07 March, 1994

in

linkedin.com/in/chaurasianeeraj

SKILLS

AWS

Linux

Kubernetes

Jenkins

Docker

Ansible

FLK

Zabbix

Mysql

Tomcat

Nginx

Apache

Vagrant

Prometheus

Grafana

Maven

Terraform

SRE

Sonarqube

LANGUAGES

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

English

Professional Working Proficiency

Neeraj Chaurasia

DevOps Engineer

I have a rich experience of 3+ years where I had hands-on expertise on multiple technologies, I have also dealt with a wide variety of use cases to implement my skills for the benefit of the organization. I have been involved in building and supporting web Saas solutions hosted on Linux/Unix platform in the cloud (AWS) as well as on-premises. Having ownership of build and release, infrastructure provisioning, monitoring, and Security.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Devops Engineer

Kronos Incorporated(Contract)

02/2020 - Present

Noida

Roles/Responsibility

- Using the Blue-Green deployments approach to upgrade the application on the production site.
- Perform pre-QA and post-QA testing to ensure application functionalities are running properly using Jenkins.
- Debugging build failures, coordinating with developers, and testers to resolve related issues.
- Using confluence to document the requirement of the upgrade process.
- Troubleshooting the issues while the deployment of the application and upgrade process.
- Using the Cloud automation tool (CAT) to launch the servers for green Deployment.
- Using Splunk to analyze log for troubleshooting.

Devops Engineer

Opstree Solutions Pvt Ltd.

05/2019 - 01/2020

Noida

Roles/Responsibility

- Managing projects with hosting Java-based Applications on cloud platform (AWS).
- Taking full ownership of Build & Release using Jenkins as a CI tool.
- Played a crucial role as an SRE (Site Reliability Engineer) with tool stack involved uptime robot, Zabbix, ELK, and Prometheus.
- Containerizing Applications in a staging environment with Docker.
- Extensively using Ansible for deployments & configuration (Redis-Sentinel, ELK) are few valueadded roles to this org.
- Managed on-prime infra (HP-Z420 Intel-Xeon) and creating VM's on Adhoc basis for the Developers using Jenkins_scripted pipeline.

System Analyst

Globallogic Technologies Pvt Ltd.

08/2016 - 01/2018

Gurugram

Roles/Responsibility

- Responsible for Day-To-Day Server administration.
- Automating launch and configure servers using Jenkins and ansible(Apache,nginx) and Mysql).
- Installing, Configuring Linux platform (Centos, RHEL, Ubuntu) Servers.
- Using shell Script to solve day-to-day admin requirements.
- User,group and Firewall security management.

EDUCATION

B.Tech(EEE)

Dr Abdul Kalam Technical University, Lucknow

08/2012 - 07/2016

10th & 12th

12th - St .Teresa School Ghaziabad (62%)

10th - Yadu Public School Noida(74.1%)